<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      version="3.7"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-7.xsd">
   <title>
      <titleInfo>Proceedings: linking healthy forests and communities through Alaska value-added forest products.</titleInfo>
   </title>
   <name type="personal" usage="primary">
      <namePart type="given">Theodore L.</namePart>
      <namePart type="family">Laufenberg</namePart>
      <displayName>Laufenberg, Theodore L.</displayName>
      <affiliation>United States Department of Agriculture, Forest Service, Forest Products Laboratory, Engineered Composites Sciences, One Gifford Pinchot Drive, Madison, WI 53726</affiliation>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <namePart type="given">Bridget K. eds.</namePart>
      <namePart type="family">Brady</namePart>
      <displayName>Brady, Bridget K. eds.</displayName>
      <role>
         <roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
   <genre>article</genre>
   <originInfo>
      <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes">2016-10-18</dateIssued>
   </originInfo>
   <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      <languageTerm type="text">English</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <abstract>The Alaska forest products industry is experiencing significant changes in its structure due to economic, ecological, and social pressures. Papers presented at this workshop brought together technical specialists and exhibitors from forest products industry, associations, universities, and private, state, and federal land management agencies. Topics included: policy and management shifts necessary to link healthy forests, communities, and industries; silvicultural concerns for future forest potential; enhancing value in lumber, engineered timber products, processing of finished wood products, and special (craft and nontimber) forest products; and assessment of Alaska forest products industry’s competitive position within state, national, and in Pacific Rim markets. As the first technology transfer event of the Wood Utilization Research and Development Center, the Alaska Value-Added Forest Products Workshop set the stage for developing a strong research and development program for the new center. The center’s mission includes working with community partners to identify and evaluate the opportunities for small businesses and examining how small businesses benefit the local economy. The Alaska Wood Utilization Research and Development Center opened in Sitka in January 1999. Congress directed its creation to identify and evaluate "value-added" activities that may provide a durable mix of employment, profits, and forest products industry in Alaska. The Center is a part of the USDA Forest Service Pacific Northwest Research Station.</abstract>
   <subject>
      <topic>Economics</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Forest management</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Timber</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Community development</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Forest products industry</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Wood utilization</topic>
   </subject>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title type="alternative">F</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
